ooh
no I don't feel confident in it at all
is difficult for even basic to get like jobs
I say research writing where doing what
I didn't find it that useful as like a creative major
as well as like an international student
yeah for people who actually take advantage of them
not me
I am Christine
I'm currently working for
a career strategist company called Elite
Share or Ling Xuan
so first I want to ask you
have you been doing any internships
I have not been doing any internships
I've applied to a couple and I've gotten like rejected
I haven't done any internships
or like proper internships
because I've always missed the date by like that much
and it's driving me a little bit insane
but hopefully I can get that work experience
not yet unfortunately
I have been on the search for like an internship but
I have not been able to get one
so yeah but here's to hoping for next summer
what do you think of the current job market right now
like do you feel confident in it
ooh
no I don't feel confident in it at all
I am slightly dreading going
if I go to Santa Barbara having to
reapply for jobs
I never felt confident entering the job market
to begin with
just because
I don't feel like I have a lot of experience
I don't expect to get a full time job straight away
like I had watched my friend
as she graduated last year and had to apply for jobs
and it took her a while before she could get anything
so I was like looking at jobs and I was like ooh
this does not look good
like there were I was applying
there was when I was applying to jobs
before I got my current job
it was like a constant ghosting
like
I would apply to a job I did submit like my resume
submit a cover letter and then no I'd hear
I wouldn't hear back from anyone
the job market right now
and the way that like
I guess HR and human resources deals with it
feels very disheartening
especially because they don't
outright tell you no
they just like ghost and that is almost worse
what has been challenging for you while job hunting
I think the scope of it
I'm sure this is true of a lot of
graduates but especially for me
if I say oh I want to go into writing
well where doing what
I say research writing where doing what
you know would I want to work full time for a company
is there specific company I want to work for like
do I want to focus on where in the work chain
am I involved in
so just the massive scope
of opportunity is very alarming
yeah that seems really difficult
to just narrow down what exactly you want to do
have you used career services on campus
at all and have you found them to be helpful
I have actually not used career services
I
did think about getting in touch with them in the fall
but I just
didn't end up ever making an appointment with them
I did go to the career fair but
I didn't find it that useful
as like a creative major
as well as like an international student
you can't like they won't guide you around by the hand
there's like a good number of career fairs I've seen
and I'm like
and the department sends the emails with like
research opportunities and internships
and those kinds of things
and like of course there's a like
department advisor you always you can always go to
so I feel like they have quite
they have good services
for people who want to like reach out to them
I see but for people who want to reach out
yeah for people who actually take advantage of them
not me
it's most helpful
when you already know what questions to ask
I know you know
all advisors are there
oftentimes just to help you identify
what questions you need to ask
before you even know which ones you need
is there any advice that you give a high schooler
who's kind of currently uncertain about their future
don't do exactly what I did but at the same time
really exploring your options I think will help you
figure out what you want to do
the easiest thing is to just put yourself out there
it's great
if you can find something that you love to do
but just like
to get the experience on some level
is probably the best
if you're less of a like
I mean right now
especially the job market being what is
at least here in the US
is difficult for even basic to get like jobs
like what is it entry level was even pretty difficult
I would have to say that like
just putting yourself out there is normally
is like a pretty great idea
what you're actually gonna get
while when you put yourself out there is debatable
but it's a journey for all of us
and it's not going to happen
if you don't take that first step